Patrick Bower

www.patrickbower.com bower.patrick@gmail.com Senior product designer working end-to-end on digital products. I bring a wealth of experience as both a practitioner and leader of design within product teams, with expertise that bridges UX, design, and engineering.

Skills

Design and UX

- Over 10 years dedicated to product design.
- Visualise complex systems into simple formats.
- Leading user research.
- · Advanced prototyping.
- · Conducting effective user testing.
- · Creating and maintaining design systems.
- · Understanding design technical limits.

Coding and Prototyping

- Five years as a dedicated front-end engineer.
- Thorough knowledge of JavaScript and React.
- · Proficient with web technology stacks.
- Solid understanding of coding best practices.
- Deep understanding of technical functions.
- Iterate prototypes into production designs.
- · Understanding of technical decision-making.

Leadership and Soft Skills

- Clear communicator of vision and strategy.
- Design and deliver presentations.
- Communicate progress and rationale to leaders
- Unlock new thinking for transformation.
- Bridge deep design and technical discussions.
- Consider user, tech and business constraints.
- Lead the product process from end to end.
- Mentor and manage team members.

Tools and Technologies

- Advanced skills with Figma and Adobe.
- Remote techniques for research in Miro.
- Maximise productivity with AI tools.
- · Dev frameworks, version control and CLIs.
- Strong Agile, Scrum, and Sprint practices.
- Gather insights with UserTesting and Hotjar.

Education

BA Visual Communication | Design

Birmingham UCE | 2001 - 2004

Achieved 2:1 with immediate work placement.

Experience

RAC | Lead Product Designer

Remote Contract | June 2023 - Sep 2024 (1 yr 3 mths)

Conducted a six-month redesign and replatforming of over 500 marketing pages. A strategic UX and design process resulted in a 9% average decrease in bounce rate, an 8% average increase in traffic, and a 3% increase in self-service channels, leading to a 1.5% reduction in call centre volume. Delivered workshops and presentations to senior business leaders while reporting to the Product Director to communicate progress and rationale. Integrated over 50 components into a nascent design system, establishing and documenting best practices.

DAZN | Senior Product Designer

London | Sep 2020 - May 2023 (2 yrs 8 mths)

Led the design of greenfield projects often driving through ambiguity, adapting the approach to fit changing needs. I used code prototypes to test and improve complex systems in context. Projects include authentication across mobile, web, and living room platforms, to deliver account ownership globally to 15 million users in over 200 countries.

Buildit | UX Engineer

London | Mar 2018 - Sep 2020 (2 yrs 6 mths)

While working with Fortune 500 companies, I led the design of new products for organisations such as Lloyds Bank, BP, and GSK. I introduced clients to user-centric ways of thinking and working to develop product strategies that enable their transformation journeys.

DD (acquired by EY) | Front End Engineer

London | Mar 2018 - Sep 2020 (2 yrs 6 mths)

Worked on projects for multinationals and start-ups, including creating a component library used by millions of users across global applications using React.js for Vodafone. I was chosen for European travel to deliver education and adoption across development hubs.

Freelance | Product Designer

London | Aug 2010 - Nov 2012 (2 yrs 3 mths)

Worked with clients including Firebrand, Glock, UAL, ASOS, and FIFA.

Boutique Agencies | Designer

London & Birmingham | Feb 2005 - Jul 2010 (5 yrs 5 mths)

Worked with clients including BBC, Universal, AEG and Fenchurch.